{
    "id": "a049016bf4ec43e3808318d047674311",
    "title": "Combine using relative pronouns",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "a27c487e477f467fa01ee058bac8e21a",
            "title": "Relative Pronouns Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I saw a castle ........... was very beautiful.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "which",
                        "that",
                        "what"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have a friend ....................... I like very much.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "whom",
                        "him",
                        "which"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The boy ......................... teased another boy was punished by the teacher.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "who",
                        "whom",
                        "which"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "A leader ......................... is sincere is loved by his followers.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "who",
                        "that",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We met a traveler ............................. told us many interesting stories.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "who",
                        "whom",
                        "him"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Air .................... is essential for life is present everywhere.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "which",
                        "that",
                        "what"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Those students ........................... had been wasting their time over trifles failed their test.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "who",
                        "whom",
                        "they",
                        "them"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the house ............................. I purchased from Mathews.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "that",
                        "which",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the woman ....................... we were talking about.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "who",
                        "whom",
                        "that",
                        "All of the above"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is an author ....................... books are so popular.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "whom",
                        "whose",
                        "who's"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}